hamidashita kaze wo atsumete mitai na
I want to try and gather the unrestrained winds
nami no saki tsutatte kanata e kaketeku
I'll run toward the horizon alongside the wave crests
kakugo wa kimatteru
I've made my decision
michi wa tookutemo
even if there's a long way to go on that road
egaita mirai e tsudzuiteru
I'll continue towards the future I've planned
toki ga bokura wo sekashite kodou ga supiido agetetta
time rushes us, the heartbeat speeds up
yume no naka de mezametemo onaji hikari wo sagashita
when I woke in the middle of a dream, I kept searching for that same light
kagayaku hoshizora no shita kazoekirenai seiza to kage
under the shining star-lit sky, with countless constellations and shadows
sono saki ni kimi wa nani wo nani wo mitsumete iru darou
there was something beyond that, what were you gazing at?
nani wo mitsumete iru darou
what were you gazing at?
Where's Naruto?
It's no good. I can't find him.
I see.
He's not close by anymore.
Either he drifted away...
or he has escaped.
At any rate, with this fog...
There's no reason
to remain here any longer.
Let's make it to a shore nearby
and start again.
Understood.
The Closed Door
It's been a while, Orochimaru-sama.
It truly has.
To think I'd stop by
on a whim to find you still here.
And it's for that reason
that I am able to meet with you again.
So, does the fact
that you're here mean
you're still continuing that research?
Yes.
And I think someday it will be
of help to you, Orochimaru-sama.
I wonder if that's true.
And all this is due to my loyalty.
Do whatever you like.
Thank you.
By the way,
is he the one
you were talking of earlier?
Yes, he's Itachi Uchiha's younger brother.
Oh, really...
Yes, my...
Please don't...
say anything unnecessary!
It appears
that Naruto is no longer close by.
Hey...
Naruto, surely he's safe, isn't he...?
He can't be beaten that easily.
After all, he too is a Leaf Shinobi.
"SHIRAGIKU INN"
I'm responsible for guarding
the ships collecting funds.
I'm Hitode.
I know the circumstances,
your colleague has disappeared
and I'm sure that you're worried.
Have you received
any information since then?
I'm sorry,
but there's been no information
regarding a victim rescued
from a shipwreck.
I see.
However, I'm troubled.
This is difficult to say,
but the departure of the collection ships
has been pushed forward.
Pushed forward?
Now we're scheduled
to leave tomorrow morning.
We apologize for our late notice.
As expected,
a large number of people find
the relationship
with Land of Water very important,
and we had to push
the departure forward.
I understand.
But we'd like to take time here
to seek and investigate
our colleague.
Of course.
We'll meet you directly
at the port tomorrow
for guard duty.
Thank you for cooperating.
— Just one thing.
— Yes?
As you can see,
we are not a very wealthy country.
We and the fishermen are both concerned
about the disturbance
of this Demon of the Ocean.
We greatly appreciate your help
with our country.
I understand.
That's right, I...
— You've come to?
— Yeah...
Hey, you're the girl from yesterday!
I get it now!
You saved me, thank you!
It just happened.
No, seriously, you saved me.
Oh, I'm Uzumaki Naruto.
What's your name?
Isaribi.
So, Isaribi, you're the girl
who saved my life.
Why did you come
to this remote area?
A mission, of course!
To exterminate the Demon of the Ocean
that has been troubling this country!
It would be best to quit.
You won't get away easily
if you get involved.
You don't need to worry.
Anyway, this is a mission.
We were careless yesterday,
but next time we'll catch
that Demon of the Ocean...!
That's hot!
So, you feel fine now?
Yep! Thanks to you,
it's excellent!
Then, once you've eaten that, get out.
Huh? What? What?
Wait, Isaribi!
Hey! Isaribi... Wait...
Huh, wha...?
"MONSTER! GO AWAY!"
What's this?
It's the work of some brats
from the village.
If I let it bother me,
there's no end to it.
Oh, Isaribi...
Really, thank you so much.
— She's out, the monster!
— What the...?
Get out of here!
You're bad luck!
Take this!
Isaribi...
Stop it, brats!
— Disappear!
— Get out of here!
Say something!
Hey, stop! All of you!
You're taking your pranks
a little too far!
Who are you?!
A friend of this monster?!
— Monster?
— Everyone's saying it.
Isaribi was spirited away
and became friends
with the Demon of the Ocean!
Don't say such irresponsible things!
It's true!
Ouch!
— Run!
— Stupid guy!
— Hey! Who you calling stupid?!
— Stop!
What?! But...
It's okay...
Leave me alone.
I can't leave you alone!
If they keep doing that...
I'm saying that it's none
of your business!
I'm the girl who was spirited away.
So, it's natural
that people find me creepy.
But that's not your fault!
That doesn't matter.
Humans don't let
those who are different from them
into their group.
So...
Your colleague was lost at sea.
We thought that if a boat left port
between the evening and morning,
maybe they saw something.
Sorry, but I don't think I can help.
Because of the Demon of the Ocean,
people of this village stay away
from the port at those times.
I see.
He's been spirited away.
That Demon of the Ocean
took someone away again.
Mother, don't say such reckless things.
Spirited away...
I heard that at the port, too.
Can you give me details
about this "spiriting away"?
What good will talking about it do?
— But...
— Please forgive me.
This isn't something
to be talked about with outsiders.
Can we do something about that, please?
We came here to exterminate
the Demon of the Ocean.
Exterminate the Demon of the Ocean?
I see.
For a long time,
there's been a legend
among fishermen on Demon Island.
A legend?
Yes, the legend says,
don't come near Demon Island,
the island where demons live.
Demon Island has always been
a fishing area rich in fish,
but there were many hidden reefs
and it was a dangerous marine area.
So, everybody obeyed the legend.
But one unusually cool summer,
about ten years ago,
the fish disappeared from the sea.
We couldn't help it,
so my husband and I set our feet
into the dangerous marine area.
It was a large catch.
But when I happily came
to the surface of the ocean,
I saw an empty boat
with my husband nowhere to be seen.
Ever since then, one after the next,
anyone who approached
that island disappeared.
Also, people who went
to search didn't return.
Since then, people from the village
stay away from the island
where spiriting away occurs.
An island nobody goes near...
That's a peculiar story.
Speaking of which, I heard that
there's a girl who returned
from being spirited away.
Oh, yes... Isaribi.
Ma'am, I've got another favor.
Please tell me where she lives!
Tsunade-sama.
Tsunade-sama!
Yes?
Gee. Here's the data you requested.
That's the Land of Sea's...
You're worried, after all.
Well, yes...
The Land of Sea is where Anko,
abandoned by Orochimaru, was found.
Hey! Are you okay?
It's no good. I can't remember.
Even though I should know...
it's dark and cold.
I was in pain, but...
Calm down.
Try taking a little more time.
I'm sure I even got this strange mark
while there.
The suggestion is deep.
Her entire memory is most likely all...
That's enough.
You've had some tough times.
It's okay.
Right now, we'll treat this Curse Mark
that's eating away at you.
We have to do that first.
Lord Hokage.
I...
In the end, her memory didn't return.
A part of Anko's memory
remains lost even now.
So, that's what happened.
So, this is the first time Anko's been
to the Land of Sea since that incident?
Yes... That's right.
It would be nice
if it could be a catalyst
for bringing back her memories.
What?!
Missed each other?!
They came here?!
Yeah, you should follow them right away!
And which way did they go?
That way!
That's the direction I came!
Damn! Everybody wait up!
The collection ship is moving.
I see, the only girl who returned
from being spirited away.
I thought we should at least go see.
She may have some information
about Demon Island!
Stop!
That girl!
Sensei!
I wonder where she intends to go.
She's cautious.
Let's follow without being noticed.
Hey, everybody! Oh, come on.
If I keep going like this,
I'll go all the way
to Isaribi's house again.
That appearance...
It can't be.
You're the Demon of the Ocean?
What?!
I won't let you escape!
Orochimaru-sama... This is...?
I'm going to teach you
something special.
This is one of the rooms
where I develop Jutsu.
I'd like you to help, too.
But... if the village knew about this...
It's not going as smoothly as I hoped.
It only needs one more step.
Silly, there's nothing to be afraid of.
The really frightening thing is
to neglect pursuing the truth.
That girl, could she be...?
Give it up! You can't escape!
You were the Demon of the Ocean!
Hey, everyone!
Hey!
I finally found you!
Naruto, you're safe.
But, Naruto, you're too late.
Too late?
We caught the Demon of the Ocean!
Look, this is it.
So, this is the Demon of the Ocean.
Isaribi...
Isaribi... You're Isaribi, aren't you?!
Naruto! What are you talking about?!
Just wait! Isaribi!
Isaribi, answer me!
— Damn it!
— Wait up, you!
Wait, don't be rough.
An explanation can wait.
We're in trouble
if we let her escape here.
Who are you?! Give Isaribi back!
Like that will happen!
She's an important guinea pig.
If she's lost, I'm responsible for it.
Bastard!
Don't chase too far!
It'll be yesterday all over again!
But...!
Crap!
No question about it.
That girl...
Sensei!
What in the world is going on?!
kaze ga fuite aa
the wind blows
itai kienai omoi
the pain, the memories won't disappear
nani wo motte ikou ka
what should be brought along?
atsumete hitotsu
assemble them into a piece
nido to nai nido to nai
there is no second chance, never
suteru nante baka mitai
how foolish it is to throw away
mujaki ni natte aa
acting so innocently
imeeji
the images
kitto sore wa owaranai
it probably will not end
ai no mune kogase
burn that love-filled heart
sen no yume watare
sail across a thousand dreams
juuoumujin kakete
running freely
te ni tsukamu sekai
to take hold of the world in hand
kumo ga chigirete
the clouds scatter
hi ga mata ochite
the sun sets yet again
hitori no pareedo ga ugokidasu
the solo parade begins to move
bouken kichijitsu shinpaku joushou
adventure, lucky day, geart beat, rising
meian souguu seimei souai
decisive, encounter, life, mutual love
Geez! What the heck
are you thinking?!
What do you intend to do alone?!
But I can't Just leave her be!
Even If you were to go after her,
you don't even have any leads
in the first place!
No, not quite!
— What?!
It seems there's an island at
the center of this land's spiriting away.
I get it. Demon Island!
Let's go after her! As for me,
I can't just leave her be!
Next time:
"Infiltrate: the Set Trap."